Guide to the Ricardo Sánchez Papers, 1941-1995
Department of Special Collections
- SERIES IV: Subject Files.
  - Subseries #1. General files
    - Proposals and Applications: Texas Commission on the Arts, "Artists in Education" application (1986) (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Puerto Rican Media Action and Education Council (1975) (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Raices de Mexico (1992) (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Raza del Norte, Pullman, WA (1992) (Box 66, Folder 5)
      Felipe (Phil) Durán
    - La Raza Unida (1989) (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - La Raza Unida - First National Convention (Rogelio Felix) (1972) (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - La Raza Unida de Aztlán, Leavenworth Federal Penitentiary (1978) (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Rehabilitation Research Foundation, "The Draper E & D Project" (1964-1968) (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Relampago Books (n.d.) (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - La Resistencia (1988) (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Revolución Artística y Acción Social, Inc. (RAYAS) (n.d.) (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Rio Grande Institute (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - Rocky Mountain Social Sciences Association (1973) (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - ROD Enterprises (National Hispanic Heritage Month) (1992) (Box 66, Folder 15)
    - Rodarte, Frank, UNIDOS talent agency (1985-1987, n.d.) (Box 66, Folder 16)
    - Rodriguez, Johnny (n.d.) (Box 66, Folder 17)
    - Rodriguez, Manolo (1973) (Box 66, Folder 18)
    - Rodriguez, Patricia, Art Festival (1980) (Box 66, Folder 19.1)
      slides and photgraphs of work
    - Rodriguez, Santiago (Box 66, Folder 19.2)
    - Romero, Gilberto (1978) (Box 66, Folder 20)
    - Rosa Guerrero International Ballet Folklorico (1990) (Box 66, Folder 21)
    - Rosas, Carlos (1972-1991) (Box 66, Folder 22)
      Texas Commission on the Arts Panel
    - Ruiz Productions, Inc. (n.d.) (Box 66, Folder 23)
    - Sabino greeting cards (1975-1976) (Box 66, Folder 24)
    - Saenz, Hulberto, resume (Box 66, Folder 25)
    - Salinas, Raul (Box 66, Folder 26)
    - Salt Lake City Schools (1979) (Box 66, Folder 27)
    - San Antonio Arts, miscellaneous (Box 66, Folder 28)
    - San Antonio Express News, Retail News Advertising Rates (1983) (Box 66, Folder 29)
    - San Antonio Public School District (1987) (Box 66, Folder 30)
    - San Antonio Public Library (1982-1984) (Box 66, Folder 31)
    - San Antonio Public Library (1985) (Box 66, Folder 32)
    - San Antonio Public Library (1986-1988) (Box 66, Folder 33)
    - San Elizano, Texas - First Thanksgiving (1989) (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Santa Ana College Chicano Studies (1974-1977, n.d.) (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Santa Fe Council for the Arts (1980-1981, n.d.) (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Self-Determination for D.C. (1973, n.d.) (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - "Semana de la Sociedad Chicana" (1986) (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - "Los Sembradores" exhibit brochure, Galeria de la Raza (1976) (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - SER Jobs for Progress, Salt Lake City (1980) (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - SER (1980, n.d.) (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Shrodes, Caroline, resume (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Simpson-Rodino Act (1987) (Box 67, Folder 10)
      La Resistencia
    - Socialist Workers Party (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Sociedad Herencia Puertorriqueña (1988) (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - SOCIO (Spanish Speaking Organization for Community, Organization, and Opportunity) (Salt Lake City) (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Soledad - CTF North (play, exhibit) (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Sostre, Martin (1973) (Box 67, Folder 15)
      Puerto Rican Issues
    - Southern Poverty Law Center (1990, n.d.) (Box 67, Folder 16)
    - Southwest Council of La Raza (Box 67, Folder 17)
    - Southwest Organizing Project (1991) (Box 67, Folder 18)
    - Southwest Training Center (Box 67, Folder 19)
    - The Spanish Connection - Complete Marketing Services (Box 67, Folder 20)
    - Spokane Community College - Students of Color Conference (1994) (Box 67, Folder 21)
    - "Stand and Deliver" production information and miscellaneous - Edward James Olmos, career miscellaneous (Box 67, Folder 22)
    - Stanford University Chicano Fellows Program (1974-1975) (Box 67, Folder 23)
    - State Arts Council of Oklahoma (1978) (Box 67, Folder 24)
    - STILL (America's Uncommon Places) (Box 67, Folder 25)
      KBDI-tv 12 Edward James Olmos (narrator)
    - Strathdee, Jim and Jean - In Music Ministry (Box 67, Folder 26)
    - Stripes, James, resume (Box 67, Folder 27)
    - Sunn, Michael - artwork (1992) (Box 67, Folder 28)
    - Supervisors of Education Conference (1976) (Box 67, Folder 29)
    - Tamayo Restaurant - Los Angeles (1988) (Box 67, Folder 30)
    - Task Force on Hispanic American Arts (n.d.) (Box 67, Folder 31)
    - El Teatro Campesino (1985) (Box 67, Folder 32)
    - "Tejano Artists" (1976-1977) (Box 67, Folder 33)
    - Tejano Conjunto Festival (1983) (Box 67, Folder 34)
    - Tejano Music Awards (1981-1982) (Box 67, Folder 35)
    - Tejano Music Awards (1984) (Box 67, Folder 36)
    - Tejano Music Awards (1985) (Box 67, Folder 37)
    - Tejano Music Awards (1986-1987) (Box 67, Folder 38)
    - Tejano Music Awards (1988) (Box 67, Folder 39)
    - Tejano Music Awards - photos (n.d.) (Box 67, Folder 40)
    - Tejanos for [against] Hunger (1985) (Box 67, Folder 41)
    - Tello, Victor (1988) (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Texas Alliance for Human Needs (1987) (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Texas Commission on the Arts - Literature Advisory Panel (1984) (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Texas Commission on the Arts - Literature Advisory Panel (1985) (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Texas Commission on the Arts - Minority Arts Conference (n.d.) (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Texas Farm Workers (1975) (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Texas Folklife Festival (1985) (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Texas Foreign Language Association (1971) (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Texas Indian Commission - Texas American Indian Sesquicentenial Association (TAISA) (1985-1989) (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Texas Institute of Letters (1974) (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - The Texas Slough (1975, n.d.) (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Texas Talent Radio Network (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - Tooele Chicano Study Committee (Utah) (1974) (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - Treviño, Flavio and Raul Servín (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Tri-Cities - student infor cards (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - "A Tribute to El Indio" (1985) (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - TRUCHA Publications, Inc.(1975, n.d.) (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - Tusin, Jack (1986) (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - Twelve Travellers (Box 68, Folder 19)
    - UEA Minority Affairs Committee (Box 68, Folder 20)
    - Union Graduate School (1971-1973) (Box 68, Folder 21)
    - Union Graduate School (1974) (Box 68, Folder 22)
    - Union Graduate School (1975-1980) (Box 68, Folder 23)
    - Union Graduate School - Jose Armas (1) (Box 68, Folder 24)
    - Union Graduate School - Jose Armas (2) (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Union Graduate School - Jose Armas (3) (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Union Graduate School - Daniel Castro (1) (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Union Graduate School - Daniel Castro (2) (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Union Graduate School - Luis Diaz de Leon (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Union Graduate School - Angela Gilliam (1) (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Union Graduate School - Angela Gilliam (2) (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Union Graduate School - Pat Gender (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Union Graduate School - Hank Mc Cord (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Union Graduate School - Dale Mc Collough (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Union Graduate School - William F. Santiago-Valles (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Union Graduate School - Eugene Speller (1) (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Union Graduate School - Eugene Speller (2) (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Union Graduate School - Steve Stamos (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Union Graduate School - The Union Institute Newsletter, The Network (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - United Farm Workers (1987) (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - United States Committee for Justice to Latin American Political Prisoners (1972-1975) (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Universidad de Campesinos Libres (1973) (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - University of Alaska, Juneau (1979) (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - University of California at San Diego (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - University of El Paso (n.d.) (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - University of Nevada, Las Vegas (1973-1974) (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - University of Pittsburgh Press - Starrett Prize, Pitt Poetry Series (1986) (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - University of Utah - book orders (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - University of Utah - course evaluations (1979-1980, n.d.) (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - University of Utah - course: "Chicano - American Experience" (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - University of Utah - course: "Chicano Contemporary Expression" (1978-1980) (Box 70, Folder 16)
    - University of Utah - course: "Chicano Thought" (Box 70, Folder 17)
    - University of Utah - course: "Culture and History of La Raza" (Box 70, Folder 18)
    - University of Utah - course: "Introduction to Chicano Studies" (Box 70, Folder 19)
    - University of Utah - course: "The Mexican Revolution" (1977) (Box 70, Folder 20)
    - University of Utah - courses: student papers (Box 70, Folder 21)
    - University of Utah - academic appointments (Box 70, Folder 22)
    - University of Utah - miscellaneous, Chicano Student assemby, Center for Ethnic Student Affairs, Chicano Student Association (Box 70, Folder 23)
    - University of Utah - miscellaneous, Chicano studies (Box 70, Folder 24)
    - University of Utah - miscellaneous, graduate study (1980) (Box 70, Folder 25)
    - University of Utah - miscellaneous, relations with South Africa (Box 70, Folder 26)
    - University of Utah - miscellaneous, Ethnic Studies Department (Box 70, Folder 27)
    - University of Utah - miscellaneous, Brad Barret Incident (1978) (Box 70, Folder 28)
    - University of Utah - miscellaneous (Box 70, Folder 29)
    - Urista, Alberto H. (Alurista) (Box 70, Folder 30)
    - Ursa Major Science Fiction Literary Association (n.d.) (Box 70, Folder 31)
    - U.S. Education Department [sic], Hispanic Concerns Staff (1980) (Box 70, Folder 32)
    - U.S. Federal Bureau of Prisons - artist in residence program (AIR) (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - U.S.A. vs. Nevada Resort Association, et. al, Consent Decree (1971) (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Utah Arts Council (1979) (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Utah Endowment for the Humanities (n.d.) (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Utah - Media (1977, n.d.) (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Utah Museum of Fine Arts (1979) (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Villa de San Fernando Historical Society (1985) (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Valdez, Luis, Teatro Campesino (1974-1978) (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Vásquez, Abraham, "A Little Spice" (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Vento, Arnold C., resume (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - ViAztlan - Centro Cultural Aztlan, San Antonio (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Villarreal, Jose (1973) (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Volunteer Lawyers and Accountants for the Arts (1985) (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - The War on Drugs (1988) (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - Washington State University (1990-1994) (Box 71, Folder 15.1)
    - Washington State University, El Gato Chicano - Hispanic Student Center Newsletter (1991-1994) (Box 71, Folder 15.2)
    - Washington State University Commission on Hispanic Affairs (1991) (Box 71, Folder 16.1)
    - Washington State University, Native American Studies (1979-1982) (Box 71, Folder 16.2)
    - Washington State University, student life (1992-1993) (Box 71, Folder 16.3)
    - Western States Arts Foundation (1981) (Box 71, Folder 17)
    - Westside Concerned Parents Group, Salt Lake City, Utah (1979) (Box 71, Folder 18)
    - Whitehouse, Betty (n.d.) (Box 71, Folder 19)
    - Wilson, Gene-K (1991) (Box 71, Folder 20)
    - Workshop Participants - unidentified events (Box 71, Folder 21)
    - Writers Workshop, Black Arts Center (Houston) (n.d.) (Box 71, Folder 22)
    - Writer-in-Residence Descriptive Report (1975-1976) (Box 71, Folder 23)
    - Writing Competitions, miscellaneous (Box 71, Folder 24)
    - Xicanindio (Box 71, Folder 25)
    - Xicanindio Art Festival and Pow-Wow (n.d.) (Box 71, Folder 26)
    - Yevtushenko, Yevgeny (1994) (Box 71, Folder 27)
    - YWCA El Paso (1988) (Box 71, Folder 28)
    - Zapata Park (Box 71, Folder 29)
  - Subseries #2. Computer diskettes and printouts
    - CHIAPAS disk (Box 71, Folder 30)
    - CHIAPAS: printout from disk, file name "CHISEZL1. NOTEBOOK" (1994) (Box 71, Folder 31)
    - CHIAPAS: printout from disk, file name "CHISART1. NOTEBOOK" (1994) (Box 71, Folder 32)
    - CHIAPAS: printout from disk, file name "CHISDIG1. NOTEBOOK" (1994) (Box 71, Folder 33)
    - CHIAPAS: printout from disk, file name "CHISFND1. NOTEBOOK" (1994) (Box 71, Folder 34)
    - CHIAPAS: printout from disk, file name "CHISORG1. NOTEBOOK" (1994) (Box 71, Folder 35)
  - Subseries #3. Oversized materials
    - Aidé de León - Canto Aide (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - Nepthtalí de Leon (Box 125, Folder 2)
    - Lewis LeRoy, "hate mail" (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - Ernesto Martinez (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - Paperbacks... y más! - Poets of Tejas, publicity materials (Box 125, Folder 5)
    - La Raza Unida (Box 125, Folder 6)
    - La Resistencia - Revolutionary Worker (Box 125, Folder 7)
      Simpson-Rodino Act
    - Posters announcing cultural events (Box 125, Folder 8)
- SERIES V: Publications by Sánchez.
  - Subseries #1. Newspapers columns and articles
    - San Antonio Express-News (1985) (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - San Antonio Express-News (1986) (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - San Antonio Express-News (1987) (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - San Antonio Express-News (1988-1990, n.d.) (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - El Paso Herald-Post (1988-1989) (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - El Paso Herald-Post (1990-1991) (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Subseries #2. Articles and poems in periodicals
    - 1969-1971 (Box 72, Folder 7)
      Washington Afro-American Carbunkle Review Tabula Rasa Quetzal Ahora
    - 1972 (Box 72, Folder 8)
      Nosotros (June) Native America '72
    - 1973 (Box 72, Folder 9)
      Magazín (vol 1, no 8, January); El Cuaderno (vol 3, no 2, Spring); El Grito del Sur (NMSU) (vol 2, no 3, March); poems to Ernesto Martínez
    - 1974 (Box 72, Folder 10)
      El Mestizo (vol 1, no 1, January); La Raza Habla (vol 1, no 4, March)
    - 1975 (Box 72, Folder 11)
      El Poder de la Luz (vol 1, no 1, November); Literatura Cultura/Literature Culture; La Luz: National Review of La Raza (March-April)
    - 1976 (Box 72, Folder 12)
      Educación es Liberación (CUFA Newsletter)
    - 1977 (Box 72, Folder 13)
      La Onda (December); El Fuego Nuevo (April); The Crossroads Advocate (Winter 77-78)
    - 1978 (Box 72, Folder 14)
      Living Colors ;Papel de Estraza; Revista Chicano-Riqueño; La Luz; Cedar Rock
    - 1979 (Box 73, Folder 1)
      Lemon Creek Gold: A Journal of Prison Literature
    - 1980 (Box 73, Folder 2)
      Papel de Estraza
    - 1981-1982 (Box 73, Folder 3)
      The National Hispanic Journal
    - 1983 (Box 73, Folder 4)
      Touchstone; Window Magazine; Austin Mardi Gras
    - 1984 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - 1985-1987 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 73, Folder 7)
      Counterattack! (Refuse and Resist) Uptown Network (El Paso)
    - 1992-1994 (Box 73, Folder 8)
      SA: An Opinionated Journal of Opinionated Essays
    - (n.d.) (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Concept Magazine (1987) (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Concept Magazine (1988) (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - ViAztlán (1983-1984) (Box 73, Folder 12)
      may include issues without Sánchez pieces
    - ViAztlán (1984) (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - ViAztlán (1985-1986) (Box 73, Folder 14)
      may include issues without Sánchez
    - ViAztlán (1986-1987) (Box 73, Folder 15)
  - Subseries #3. Books and pamphlets by Sánchez
    - Amerikan Journeys::Jornadas Americanas (1993) - Proof copies (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Amsterdam Cantos y poemas pistos (1983) (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - BERTRAND & THE MEHkQOVERSE: a XicAno Filmic Nuance (1983) (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Brown Bear Honey Madness (?) (1979) (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Dr. Sánchez' All-You-Can-Eat Poetry Buffet (1994) (photocopy) (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Dr. Sánchez' All-You-Can-Eat Poetry Buffet or Lentils of Revolution (1994) (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Journeys through the Pass: BLOODIED TRACKS & DESERTLAND POEMS (1990) (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Mano a Mano (n.d.) - Co-authored with Juan Contreras (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Perdido: A Barrio Story (1985) (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - "Perdido: A Barrio Story" (1985) OVERSIZED Materials (Box 126)
      Rob Lewis, publisher.
    - book jacket for Canto y Grito mi Liberación (Box 126)
  - Subseries #4. Introductions, etc.
    - Introduction to Buscando the Key, ed. by Merrill Franklin Danford (1993) (Box 74, Folder 10)
      Also includes "las shards shamas" by Sánchez
    - Introduction to La Chicana, by Gloria Treveño (1978) (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Introduction to Chicano: 25 pieces of a chicano mind, by Abelardo (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - "i yearn," in Chicano Voices, ed. by Carlota Cárdenas de Dwyer (1975) (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - "Thought to the Art of Ernesto Martinez," in El Mejor Pintor Que Tiene Nuestra Raza, by Reies López Tijerina (1974) (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Introductions to Míctla: The Ninth Level of Death, vols. 1 and 2 (1972) (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - "mi raza es..." in POINTS OF DEPARTURE, by Ernece B. Kelly (1972) (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - Introduction to Shades of Crimson (1994) (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Introduction to Why Am I So Brown?, by Trinidad Sánchez, Jr. (Box 75, Folder 2)
- SERIES VI: Manuscripts by other authors.
  - Subseries #1. Manuscripts about Sánchez
    - Adame, María Delia, "Auto-Definition and Affirmation in in Ricardo Sánchez" (1977) (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Carillo, Leonardo, "Sound and the Artistic Expression in Ricardo Sánchez." (1977) (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Castillo, Rafael C, "The Ricardo Sánchez Poetry Club" (n.d.) (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Danford, Merrill Franklin, "Poetics - a Paper" (n.d.) (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - de Léon, Nephtalí, "The Great Philosophical Song of Liberation" [review of AMSTERDAM CANTOS y poemas pistos] (1983) (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - de Léon, Nephtalí, review of AMSTERDAM CANTOS y poemas pistos (n.d.) (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Delgado, Abelardo B, "A Review of Ricardo Sánchez's "Hechizospells" (n.d.) (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Freed, Jo Ann, "Existentialism: as seen in the poetry of Ricardo Sánchez (n.d.) (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Garcia, Gloria, "The Image of the Woman in Ricardo Sánchez" [ (1977) (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Haddox, John H, "Introduction [to a book by Sánchez?] (1990s) (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - Haddox, John H, Review of HechizoSpells (1970) (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - Keene, Tom, "Paperbacks...Y Mas" (1984) (Box 75, Folder 14)
    - Sánchez, Josefa, "Everyone Has a Right to Have a Dream" (1986) (Box 75, Folder 15)
    - Stefanile, Felix, Letter to David about NEA grants, fellowships (1980) (Box 75, Folder 16)
    - Tamez, Gonzalo, "Ricardo Sánchez's View of the Establishment" (1977) (Box 75, Folder 17)
    - Taylor, Charles [Chuck], "I am a Man who is a Poet: a Portrait and Interview with Ricardo Sánchez" (1978?) (Box 75, Folder 18)
    - Vento, Arnoldo, "LA VOZ POETICA SANCHIANA: Canto, Grito y Danza Universal" (1986) (Box 75, Folder 19)
    - Zimmerman, Enid, "Ricardo Sánchez" (1981) (Box 75, Folder 20)
    - Author unknown, "El Arte de Ricardo Sánchez: Un Perspectivo Social" (1980s) (Box 75, Folder 21)
    - Authors unknown, Incomplete critiques of Sánchez's work (Box 75, Folder 22)
  - Subseries #2. Miscellaneous poetry and prose
    - Aburto, Salvador, "...A Few Poems Reflecting a Part of Me From May Through Nov. 1971...." (Box 75, Folder 23)
    - Acosta, Jess, "Cuenta Conmigo," "Count on Me" (n.d.) (Box 75, Folder 24)
    - Alvarez, Rolando T., aka Alvaro de Villa, Various writings (Box 75, Folder 25)
    - Anzuldua, Gloria. Discussion with Irina about Borderlands (1987) (Box 75, Folder 26)
    - Aragon, John, "An Impediment to Cultural Pluralism: Culturally Deficient Educators Attempting to Teach Culturally Different Children" (n.d.) (Box 75, Folder 27)
    - Atencio, Tomás and Alberto Lovato. "Modelo Educacional de la Academia" (n.d.) (Box 75, Folder 28)
    - Barrios, Gregg, "Dead End Again" (1985) (Box 75, Folder 29)
    - Barrios, Gregg, "Carrasco!" (1975) (Box 75, Folder 30)
    - [Bill ?], "You know, Man..." (1970) (Box 75, Folder 31)
    - Blea-Morena, Irene, "Celebrating, Crying and Cursing: A Chicana Lament" (n.d.) (Box 75, Folder 32)
    - Begishe, Kenneth Y, et al, "A Programmed Guide to Navajo Transcription" (1967) (Box 75, Folder 33)
    - Bernal, Adrian, "Los Aztecas" (1986) (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Bernal, Adrian, "To Ricardo" (n.d.) (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Bernal, Adrian, miscellaneous poetry (n.d.) (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Blade, John Ramage, Poetry and prose (1978-1981) (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Bowman, Tonny, "The Basic Principles of Potential American Indian Police Power - Over Economic Development on Reservations" (1976) (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Briggs, E. Tavon, "ON THE CORNER: A one - act play" [includes correspondence] (1986) (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Caballero, Raul, "¿Que Clase de Sueño te Traes?" (n.d.) (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Canales, Eugenio Jr., "Selected Works" (1988) (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Cannon, Nora, "Poems" (1975) (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Castañeda, William, "Sanctuario" (n.d.) (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Castillo, Ana, Poetry (1975-1981) (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Chávez, Denise, "Nacimiento" (n.d.) (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Conals [?], Josephine Clair, Poetry (1984) (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Contreras, Juan A., "Reflecciones Hacia Mi Barrio" (1973) (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Cotera, Martha P, "Mexican American Literature: A Preliminary List" (1970) (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - Courtney, Yolanda Reed, "The Audience" (n.d.) (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - de Hoyos, Angela, Poetry and drawings (1975-1977) (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - De León, Nephtalí, "Aztlan Fairy Tales/ Fabulas de Aztlan" (n.d.) (Box 76, Folder 18)
    - De León, Nephtalí, "Guadalupe Blues" (1985) (Box 76, Folder 19)
    - De León, Nephtalí, "On The State of Chicano Arts" (n.d.) (Box 76, Folder 20)
    - De León, Nephtalí, "On The Human Condition..." (n.d.) (Box 76, Folder 21)
    - De León, Nephtalí, "El Tesoro de Pancho Villa" (1977) (Box 76, Folder 22)
    - Doria, [?], Various writings (1982?) (Box 76, Folder 23)
    - Durán, Felipe Hector, "Mi Tributo" (1992) (Box 76, Folder 24)
    - Durán, Felipe Hector, Poetry readings (1992) (Box 76, Folder 25)
    - Durán, Roberto, Poetry (n.d.) (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Eckhous, Lauren, "Latinos: Making Waves in Public Radio" (n.d.) (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Falcon, Peter Gonzales, "San Antonio Rose" (1983) (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Fenton, Lisa Howell, Poetry (1981-1988) (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Flores, Maria G, "Poemas" (1953-1979) (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Freeman, John, Poetry (1984) (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Fundora de Rodríguez Aragón, Raquel, Poetry (n.d.) (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - García, Cecilio, "I Hung a Snake on the Fence So That I'd Rain But the Coyotes Ate It" (n.d.) (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - García, Esteban Hermán, "Un Analisis de Una Novela Chicana Peregrinos de Aztlan by Miguel Mendez M. "(1977) (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - García, Patricio, Writings from jail. (1984) (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Guana, Luis Rodriguez. Poetry (1977) (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Gelabert, Ana Lucía, "Mojado Cunegundo" (1987) - pages 1-155 (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Gelabert, Ana Lucía, "Mojado Cunegundo" (1987) - pages 156-357 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Gonzales Flores, Judy, "El Corrido Fronterizo: ¿Se puede clasificar como concion de protesta social?" (1975) (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - Guerra, Jorge, "Legend of the Volcanos" (n.d.) (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Guerra, Manuel M., "The Mexican-American Child: Problems or Talents?" (1965) (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Gutiérrez y F., Alfredo, "Rosas Triangulares" (1977) (Box 77, Folder 17)